まずい
This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
まずいよ これ
昴ったら あれから一度も学校来てないんだよ
This is bad!
I'm telling you it's bad!
まっ アキちゃんも発作起こしたりして 相当まずかったけどね
Subaru hasn't come to school since then!
うちのことはどうでもいいの
It was quite a mess with you getting spasms and all.
それより 昴のことだよ
That doesn't matter now! Subaru's what matters!
こうなったら 昴の家に乗り込むしかない
やめなよ アキちゃん
Now that it's come to this,
we've got no choice but to sneak into his house!
誰もが夢を持ち続けられるわけじゃない
Cut it out, Aki.
それはアキちゃんも知ってるでしょ
Not everyone can continue having great dreams like you.
You of all people should know this.
Behind the words passing by
The key of my closed heart is hidden
If setting your flag
Could save your smile
The late summer breeze
Turns into a midday squall
As we sync our wavelengths
I'm such a bad romantic
Can't even find
Any words with an edge
Still I aim for the blue sky
We can become one
As our dreams and confused tears
Draw us ever closer to the truth
That becomes our beloved
Magical keyword
待ってろロゼッタ 夢は永遠に続くんだ
Wait for me, Rosetta! Our dream will last forever!
疾風怒濤の元気一発
Lightning speed Genki power punch!
Ah, Yashio.
八汐君
The Gunvarrel anime?
『ガンヴァレル』のアニメ？
Yeah, Akiho let me borrow it.
Thanks you very much!
あき穂ちゃんが貸してくれたから 全１５５話
All 155 episodes.
今は まだ７話だけど
Though I'm still just at episode 7.
There's still a lot ahead.
まだまだ 先は長いね
Well, it's quite fun, and the last
episode's kinda an urban legend,
でも 結構 面白いよ
それに 『ガンヴァレル』の最終回って都市伝説にもなってるから
一度全部見なきゃって思ってたし
so I've wanted to watch it all for a while now.
That mysterious last episode that never aired?
放送中止になった幻の最終話ってやつ？
You really like urban legends, don't you?
ホント都市伝説が好きだよね
Ah, by the way, remember when PokeComs were freezing all at once?
あっそういえば この前のポケコンが一斉にフリーズするって話
I looked into it, and stuff like that's happened before.
他にも 似たような現象が起きてないか調べてみたんだ
Apparently it's happened quite a few times before.
そしたら 過去にも結構あって
Stuff like millions of people getting emails at the same time.
例えば 何百万人のポケコンに一斉にメールが届くって現象とか
And the content of that mail was quite scary too.
そのメールの内容っていうのがね ちょっと怖くて
Scary?
怖いって？
Kagome Kagome
The bird in the cage
When, oh when can it come out
The night before the dawn
The crane and the turtle slip
Who's in front of behind?
Kagome Kagome
The bird in the cage
When, oh when can it come out
The night before the dawn
The crane and the turtle slip
Who's in front of behind?
It was the lyrics of "Kagome Kagome."
『かごめかごめ』の歌詞だったの
どうかした？
What's wrong?
It's... nothing...
いや 何でもな…
FRAUKOUJIRO has sent you an email.
Yashio, you should tell me when you're gonna help me hunt cheaters down.
八汐先輩は いつチーター狩りしてくれるのか教えてくれるべき
You should come to my room.
私の部屋に来ればいいじゃない
Then in my moldy room, freezing cold from the AC,
そして かび臭くてエアコンでギンギンに室温下げた部屋で
we'd play games, turned on in unladylike poses,
あられもない姿でｗｋｔｋしながら
メガネ男子をヒィヒィ言わせるみたいに ゲームすればいいじゃない
that could make glasses guys cry out in joy!
It's friggin cold...
寒っ
エアコン弱めたら？ 体 壊すよ
Why don't you turn your AC down? This'll ruin your health.
Ah, you worry about me? But I refuse!
心配してくれてるんですね
だが 断る
さ…寒いくらいの方が好きだし
I prefer cold anyway.
Would you like something to drink?
先輩 な…何か飲む？
Do you have anything warm?
あったかい飲み物
Boiling water's such a drag.
お湯 沸かすのマンドクセ
You call me here then this is what I get?
人のこと呼び出しといて それ？
Well, I've got time on my hands now that we can't go to the Robo-One after all.
まあ ＲＯＢＯ－ＯＮＥの出場はなくなりそうだし
暇になったから いいんだけどさ
Those top five on the leaderboard...
リ…リーダーボードの上位５人いるっしょ
Until last month I thought they were all cheaters.
わた…私 先月までこの５人チーターだと思ってた件
少なくとも 俺は違う
I'm not one at least.
Neither is the fourth, Tagiri.
あと ４位のタジリンもチーターじゃない
How do you know?
何で分かるん？
I know.
分かるんだよ
俺ぐらいの腕になれば 手合わせしたときの手触りで
At this level you can feel it when you fight.
それに タジリンは…
And Tagiri...
Never mind.
何でもない
それより 上３人は絶対にチート使ってる
The top three are definitely cheating.
During fights they use tricks that are clearly superhuman.
対戦中に明らかに人間業じゃない動きをすることがあるんだ
Agreed.
同意
So how do you hunt them down?
で どうやって狩るわけ？
You should just fight them.
せ…先輩は 単に相手と対戦すればいい
I made a tool that detects cheating.
チートを判別する解析ツールを作った
I'll run it while you're fighting.
対戦中 それを走らせる
How do you intend to make us fight?
どうやって対戦するつもり？
Uh...
Just wait until you get matched together?
マッチングするまで待てばいいんじゃね？
So you're telling me to wait for an opponent that might never even show up?
つまり いつ現れるかも分からない相手を待ち続けろってこと？
Who's that?
誰？
な… せ…先輩
Y-Yashio...
Subaru?
昴君 こそこそ 何やってんの
Why are you sneaking around like that?
Aki's worried about you.
アキちゃん 心配してたよ
And you? What are you doing here?
せ…先輩こそ 何やってるんですか
I was at Kona's place holding up my end of the deal.
俺はこなちゃんの所にいたの
交換条件に付き合わされたんだよ
The birthday suit photoshoot?
全裸撮影会ですか
No, hunting cheaters.
チーター狩りね
Though they didn't show up in the end, so it'll be continued tomorrow.
結局チーターは現れなくて 続きはまたあした
それ…
That is...
You made up with your dad?
父親と和解したの
As if that's possible.
そんなわけないでしょう
My dream's over.
僕の夢は終わったんです
Please tell the club president.
部長にお伝えください
I'll get rid of the M45 myself. I can sort out my feelings better that way.
やはりＭ４５は 自分で処分することにしましたと
その方が気持ちの整理ができるので
See you.
それじゃ
Brother, what have you been looking at?
お兄ちゃんは何を見ていましたか
You've been coming here for nine years now.
お兄ちゃんは９年前からよくここに来ていました
On average once every two days.
平均すると ２日に一度のペースです
Sometimes with two others, sometimes with one other, sometimes alone.
３人のときもあったし ２人のときも １人のときもありましたね
Kai, if you're a real boy, grow up into a man who has The Right Stuff.
カイ あんたも男の子なら ライトスタッフを持つ男になりなさい
I wanted to become an astronaut you know.
俺さ 宇宙飛行士になりたかったんだよね
No astronauts ever went to space from the Tanegashima Space Center.
種子島宇宙センターから宇宙へ行った人はいません
I know.
知ってるよ
But still, I'm sure every guy born on this island wants to become one at some point.
でもさ やっぱ種子島に育った男なら 一度は目指すでしょ
ミサ姉 ロボ部の部長にならないって ホント？
Misa, are you really not gonna become the Robotics club's president?
Yeah... It doesn't matter anymore.
そうね もうどうでもよくなってしまったの
But what about the giant robot?
でも 巨大ロボは？
That's just a pile of junk.
あんなの ただのがらくたよ
まっ それももう諦めたけどね。
I've given up on that already.
The EXOSKELETON corporation's newest powered suit
エグゾスケルトン社の最新型パワードスーツが
Powered suit control loss incidents continue
is reported to have lost control on several occasions.
暴走するという事故が相次いでいます
消費者庁によると
According to the consumer agency,
in the past two years there were at least a hundred cases.
過去２年間に少なくとも１００件に上る同様の事故の報告があり
Powered suit control loss incidents continue
EXOSKELETON Corp.
Public Relations
Senomiya Misaki
EXOSKELETON Corp.
Powered Suit Division Chief
Sawada Toshiyuki
As there were a number of accidents that resulted in serious injuries such as broken bones,
うち 骨折などの重傷を負う事故も数件 起きているとし
there are doubts regarding the safety of the devices. The EXOSKELETON Corpora—
安全性について重大な欠陥がなかったかどうか エグゾスケルトン社に…
Good afternoon!
こんにちは
Are you the robot doctor?
あなたがロボドクターですか
I'm Senomiya Misaki from the Tanegashima Central High Robotics circle.
私 中央種子島高校ロボット同好会の瀬乃宮みさ希といいます
There's something I'd like you to take a look at.
あなたに見てほしいものが…
助言が欲しいんです
Could you tell me your opinion?
A hobby robot?
ホビーロボか
No, I'd like to build a full-size giant robot.
違います 実物大の巨大ロボを造りたくて
Go home, and don't come again!
帰んな 二度と来んな
大人をバカにするもんじゃねえぞ 小娘
Don't you make a fool of adults, girly!
I'm not leaving.
いいえ 帰りません
I have nothing to say to you!
お前さんに教えることなど 何もない
Then how about this?
だったら…
How did it go?
大丈夫だった？
It went okay. I guess.
何とかね
I was finally able to pay off our debt.
やっと付けが返せてよかったよ
It's all thanks to our sponsors.
スポンサーさまさまだね
Thanks for tagging along, Jun.
ジュンもありがとう ついてきてくれて
ごめんなさい 私 やっぱり中には入れなくて
I'm sorry I couldn't go inside with you.
It's okay!
いいの いいの ここまで一緒に来てくれただけで 元気百倍だよ
I get a 1000% powerup from you coming along.
Anyway, now that we've got our funds,
さて 活動費も入ったことだし
we should check the parts we need in the catalogs.
必要なパーツをカタログ見て洗い出ししなきゃ
Robots are always just robots.
しょせん ロボットはロボットってことだ
Kai, this is terrible!
大変だよ カイ
You mean the control loss accident yesterday?
昨日の暴走事故のこと？
That's terrible too,
それも大変だけど そっちはお姉ちゃんがいるから 大丈夫
but my sister's there so that'll work out!
I meant Subaru!
それより 昴だよ
The M45 was gone when I dropped by the hangar earlier!
ハンガーに寄ったら Ｍ４５がなくなってたんだよ
あぁ それなら昴君が持って帰ったよ
Subaru took that with him.
He said he'll get rid of it himself.
自分で処分するってさ
昴に会ったの どうして説得しなかったの
You met Subaru?!
Why didn't you try to convince him?!
What'd be the point in that?
だから しょうがないでしょ
I told you, there's nothing we can do about this.
俺たちにはどうすることもできないって
Tell me, Gunvarrel...
ガンヴァレル
What should I do?
うちは いったいどうすればいいのかな
Subaru! Are you at home?!
昴 いる？
If you are, come out already!
いるなら出てきてよ
Subaru!
昴
涙を拭いて 顔を上げろ
Wipe your tears and raise your eyes!
You can't see the light of tomorrow otherwise!
でなきゃ あしたは見えないぜ
Hidaka
But you know, aren't you the one who made Kill-Ballad?
よく考えたらさ こなちゃんて『キルバラ』の作者だよね
天才プログラマーのフラウコウジローですお キリッ
The genius programmer Frau Koujiro at your service! Serious Face!
Could you tell me about the development while we're waiting for the match?
マッチングするまで暇だからさ 開発秘話みたいなの教えてよ
About the coding of the robots and stuff.
機体ごとのプログラムの癖とかさ
八汐先輩にはそんな情報 必要なくね？
What would you need that for?
Y-You have some special ability, you know, like what eighth-graders believe.
す…すごい能力あるでしょ 厨二病的な
すごい能力？
What special ability?
スローモーか
Ah, you mean the slow motion?
You're getting it wrong. It's just post-traumatic spasms.
勘違いしないでほしいんだけど 後発的な発作だよ あれは
It's no special ability.
能力でも 何でもない
Stuff like getting super reaction speed during the spasms?
発作起きると超反応が使えるとか アニメなら１０年前に廃れたレベル
That counted as lame in anime a decade ago.
It's not funny.
ちゃかさないでくんないかな
発作中は苦しくて死にそうになるんだ
The spasms are really tough. I feel like I could drop dead at any moment.
Don't joke about it without knowing anything.
そういうことも知らずに 好き勝手言わないでくれ
Then let's tell each other our secrets we can't tell anyone.
んじゃ さ…さらし合いしようず 誰にも言えない秘密の共有
Duhuhu.
何を
What?
Do you know why the last episode of Gunvarrel was never aired?
『ガンヴァレル』の最終回が放送中止になった理由 知ってる？
Nope. Don't care either.
知らない 別に興味ないし
It wasn't aired, because the staff died right beforehand.
ささ…最終回が放送されなかったのは 関係者がちょ…直前に死んだから
And not just one person either.
しかも１人じゃない 最低でも１３人
At least thirteen people.
Not to mention the director went missing right after.
で 直後に監督の人が行方不明になったっつーか
I lol'd when I read that they're suspecting him of being the culprit.
だから その監督が犯人じゃないかって疑われてて ワロタ
And you believe that?
そんなの信じちゃったわけ？
わた…私の本名は 古郡こな
M-My name's Furugoori Kona.
But you could also read Furugoori as Kogoori.
「ふるごおり」をもじると こごおり
The anime's director was Kogoori Minami.
アニメの監督やってた人の名前は こご～りみなみ
My mom.
私のママ
I-I'm the daughter of a murder suspect.
さ…殺人事件の容疑者の娘 それが私
Mom was last seen on this island. That's why I moved here.
ママが最後に目撃されたのがこの島
だから 私はここに引っ越してきた
That's quite a heavy story right off the bat...
ヘビーな話を さらっとぶちまけてくれるね
I'll pretend I never heard this.
今のは聞かなかったことにしとくよ
I'd rather not get invol—
厄介なことに首…
ボブリーだ ランキング３位の…
It's BOBLEE! The third place!
来ましたわ
Here he is!
So you were at Frau Bow's place instead of the hangar?
ハンガーにいないと思ったら フラウ坊の所にいたの
Yeah, doing my end of the deal.
まあね 例の交換条件ってやつ
Cheat analysis
Matches
Check logs
We couldn't find any proof of cheating. Kona was quite surprised.
でも 結局チートが使われた形跡が見つからなくて
こなちゃんは 不思議がってたけど
２人きりで？
The two of you all alone?
そうなるかな
I guess.
カイって そんなに女たらしだったっけ
When did you become such a womanizer?
Do I look like one?
そう見える？
見えない
Nope. You're only hot for games anyway.
カイが興味あるのはゲームだけだもんね
And where were you so late?
アキちゃんこそ こんな時間までどこ行ってたのさ
昴んち
I went to Subaru's house.
No one was at home though...
家の人は誰もいなかったから 大丈夫
And I was just bringing him something he forgot.
それに 忘れ物を届けに行っただけだし
He forgot something?
忘れ物？
I found it in the hangar.
ハンガーに落ちてたの
Even if he's quitting the club, that must be important to him.
たとえ ロボ部を辞めることになったとしても
あれは 昴の大切なものだから
What?
あれって？
A part of the M45.
Ｍ４５のパーツ
Summer break starts tomorrow.
あしたから夏休みが始まります
But you only have half a year until your university entrance exams,
が 受験まであと半年しかありません
so make sure to spend your summer meaningfully.
だらけた生活を送らず 有意義な夏休みにしてください
Over.
以上
万博まであと半年 この夏休みが勝負だよ
We only have half a year until the Expo.
This summer will be a real challenge for us!
Aki, were you listening at all to the teacher?
アキちゃん 先生の話聞いてた？
Subaru didn't come to school today either, so we'll have to work by ourselves.
だって 昴今日も来てないみたいだし
うちらだけで頑張んなきゃいけないんだよ
Long time no see, President.
お久しぶりです 部長
Subaru!
昴 よかった お父さんと和解できたんだね
I'm so glad! You made up with your dad, right?
My father isn't such a soft person.
僕の父親はそんな生ぬるい人間じゃありません
Officially I'm here to study in quiet.
僕がここにいるのは 静かに勉強するためということになっています
Do you seriously expect that excuse to work?
その言い訳はさすがに通用しないんじゃ
I do.
大丈夫です
I picked the M45 into pieces in front of him.
Ｍ４５を 父さんの前で解体しましたから
For that reason, we must cancel our entry at the Robo-One.
ですから ＲＯＢＯ－ＯＮＥへの出場もキャンセルです
I'm really sorry, Yashio.
八汐先輩には申し訳ありませんが
I'm not exactly devastated.
いや 俺は助かるけどね
Now I can enjoy a true Kill-Ballad summer.
これで 夏休みは『キルバラ』三昧できるし
It must've been hard.
つらかったでしょ
にゃ にゃ… ぶ…部長
P-P-President?!
うちには分かるよ 昴がどれだけつらかったか
I can fully understand how hard it must've been.
It was a part of you, your true partner!
あの子は 昴にとって分身でパートナーだもん
And you had to pick it apart yourself...
それを 自分の手で…
That said, wanna run, Subaru?!
というわけで 昴 走りますか
ほら あの夕日に向かって
Look! Into the sunset!
I don't!
走りませんよ
But...
でも…
But you tried to save the M45, and you brought me that broken part too...
でも あのときＭ４５をかばおうとしてくれて
壊れたパーツを届けてくれて
Um...
その… あ…ありがとうごじゃいました
T-Thanks you very much!
"Thanks you," huh?
「ごじゃ」
Kai, Subaru opened his heart to us!
カイ 昴が心を開いたよ
べ…別に 心を開いてなんかいませんよ
I didn't do anything of the sort!
I just thought that if I'm studying here in quiet anyway,
僕はただ ここで勉強するついでに その…
ガンヴァレル建造を少しくらいなら 手伝ってもいいかと思っただけです
I could maybe help you a little with building Gunvarrel.
こんにちは
Good afternoon!
今日はどうした ミスター・プレアデスも一緒か
What do you want today?
Ah, Mister Pleiades is with you this time?
なっ…なぜ分かったんです
How did you know?!
Anyone could see through that disguise...
あの程度の変装 誰だって分かるに決まってんじゃねーか
What were you thinking?
寝ぼけてんのか
Anyone?! No way...
「誰だって」って そんなバカな
So, what do you want?
で 今日は何の用だ
No way... No way... No way...
そんな
We came to buy parts!
パーツ 買いに来ました
For a hobby robot?
ホビーロボのか
No! For the GunPro-1!
違うよ ガンつく１のパーツ
だったら 賭けをしませんか
Then how about this? Let's make a bet!
A bet?
賭け？
ロボット同好会は ことし中にＲＯＢＯ－ＯＮＥで優勝します
The Robotics circle will win the Robo-One this year.
If we can do that, you'll help the Robotics club with your skill and knowledge!
それが実現できたら あなたの技術と知識をロボ部に下さい
What do you say? These are all the GunPro-1's parts!
どう？ これ全部ガンつく１のパーツ
The CEO was so kind as to finance it all for us!
社長が気前よくぽんとお金出してくれたおかげだよ
ちなみに 今うちの社でステッカーを作っとる
And we're making stickers at the company!
Stickers?
ステッカー？
Yeah, one that has "Space Candy Inc" written on it in huge letters!
スペースアメ社っちゅうて ど～んと書いてあるでっかいやつだ
ボインちゃん
Put that on the most apparent spot on the robot, okay?
それをな ロボの一番目立つ所にば～んと貼ってくれ
The impact's important!
インパクトは大事じゃからな
But...
でも…
And we'd want the rider of the robot to be Junna!
あと 乗組員は わが社としては淳和ちゃんを推させてもらう
B-But... I can't do that!
む…無理です 私 そんなの…
Um, at this point the pilot's Kai...
ええと パイロットは今のところ カイに
No! A karate cutie from the island riding a giant robot
いやぁ 島出身の空手美少女が乗る巨大ロボっちゅうのはインパクトじゃから
would be real impact!
ボイン ボイン ボインパクト
つ…疲れた
I'm so tired...
I don't really like that CEO...
私 あの社長さんちょっとだけ苦手
I see the parts have arrived.
パーツ 届いたんですね
You're late, Subaru!
遅刻だよ 昴
You should check if any of them got damaged in the solar storm, just in case.
太陽嵐で壊れていないか 念のため調べた方がいいんじゃないですか
What solar storm?
太陽嵐がどうかした？
Ah, Twipo's been going on about it since this morning.
「ツイぽ」でけさから話題になってるよね
When the flare reached some machinery on...
太陽嵐が到達して えーとアメリカの西海岸で機械が壊れたとか何とか
Um... the American west coast, it all broke.
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the American west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the american west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
The foreign ministry's telling people
to cancel their flights to the american west coast #tab
Breaking! The Robo-One world championship
is canceled due to the disturbances in North America!
In 2012, 15, 19, and 20. there will be a series of gargantuan solar flares.
２０１２ １５ １９ ２０と 連続で大規模な太陽嵐が発生し
The solar flare in 2015 will have the most grave effects on Earth and its magnetosphere.
特に１５年の太陽嵐は 地球と地球磁気圏に深刻な影響を及ぼす
I wonder if we'll have another '15 Crash.
もしかして また１５年クラッシュみたいになるのかな
I wouldn't go that far yet,
そこまでは まだ
but they're saying there's an even stronger one coming soon.
でも 今後もっと強いのが来るかもしれないそうです
Scientific research concludes that the Sun will soon explode.
太陽が爆発寸前まで来ているのは紛れもない事実なのだ
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
It's Kagome Kagome!
かごめかごめ
What's this?
何？ これ
My PokeCom's doing it too!
僕のポケコンからもです
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Reject
Hidden number
Incoming call
Accept
Hidden number
Incoming call
Call Duration
Hidden number
あの
Um,
is this the Robotics Club of Tanegashima Central High School?
君たちって 中央種子島高校のロボット研究部の皆さん？
そ…そうですけど
Yes...
I know it's sudden, but I have a few questions for you.
えーと…突然ですけど お話ししたいことがあるので
Could you come along please?
一緒に来てもらえます？
The blinding light of childhood memories
Turns the scenery of my dream
Into monochrome as it lies forgotten
And vanishes from my eyes
But you've always been
Looking straight at the future
And you paid the price in tears
So we turn our hesitation
Into strength by the power
Of our connected hearts
Feel it! These overflowing emotions
For that someone in the sunset
I'll use what little courage I have
And overcome the rage of the wind
Because I want to protect you
IIIMPAAAAAAACT!
Tune in next week too!